<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on MelanieWickert.de</title>
    <link>http://melaniewickert.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on MelanieWickert.de</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 10:33:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://melaniewickert.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters Project</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 10:53:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/masters/</guid>
      <description>The effect of relatedness on group and community structure in Tanganyikan cichlids Sorry, your browser doesn&#39;t support HTML5 video.  For my Master’s thesis I investigated how the genetic relatedness of individuals influences group interactions and community structure in a social cichlid species endemic to Lake Tanganyika in Zambia. I looked at group living and nest building behaviours in Neolamprologus multifasciatus, the smallest cichlid species in the world, and endemic to Lake Tanganyika.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a biologist with a background in immunology, molecular toxicology and behaviour. Originally from the Black Forest region of Southwestern Germany, I began my studies at the University of Freiburg under Prof. Dr. Klaus Warnatz at the [Centrum für Chronische Immundefizienz (CCI)](https://www.uniklinik-freiburg.de/cci.html) , conducted my Erasmus at the University of Uppsala, and recently completed my Masters of Biological Sciences at the University of Konstanz, in the Department of Collective Behaviour at the Max-Planck-Institute for Animal Behaviour under Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interests</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 12:03:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/interests/</guid>
      <description>My first experience in research, working in a molecular immunology lab isolating b cells and evaluating their cytokine expression, fostered in me a deep interest in molecular biology. During my Erasmus I became interested in the ecological aspect of biology and took courses in limnology and marine biology. Not neglecting the molecular opportunities there, I also attended courses in human physiology and evolutionary genetics.
During my Master’s studies, I became interested in linking the broader ecological and behavioural impacts to underlying molecular mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bachelors Project</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/bachelors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/bachelors/</guid>
      <description>Cytokine production of b cells in patients with variable immune deficiency)   Copyright 2014 Melanie Wickert   For my Bachelor’s project, I investigated the Cytokine production of b cells, especially of CD 21low b cells, in a subgroup of patients with common variable immune deficiency (CVID). CVID is the most common primary immune deficiency in adults, and is characterised by recurrent infections, low antibody levels in at least 2 immunoglobulin types, and immune dysregulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 10:53:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/skills/</guid>
      <description> Cell culture, microscopy, immuno-staining, FACS, B cell isolation, cell viability assays, PCR/ qPCR, ELISA, SDS Page, Western Blot, Primer design, DNA/RNA isolation and micro-satellite analysis, genetic and behavioral data collection in the field
 Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Photoshop; Basics in GraphPad Prism, Matlab, Processing, Python, OpenCV, Java, and R
 Project planning and management, data collection and management, experimental design
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 17:45:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/contact/</guid>
      <description>Get in touch phone: +49 170 3184888
email: wickert.melanie@googlemail.com</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>