<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sections on MelanieWickert.de</title>
    <link>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sections on MelanieWickert.de</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:59:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://melaniewickert.de/sections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a biologist with a background in immunology, molecular toxicology and behaviour. Originally from the Black Forest region of Southwestern Germany, I began my studies at the University of Freiburg under Prof. Dr. Klaus Warnatz at the Centrum für Chronische Immundefizienz (CCI), conducted my Erasmus at the University of Uppsala, and recently completed my Masters of Biological Sciences at the University of Konstanz, in the Department of Collective Behaviour at the Max-Planck-Institute for Animal Behaviour under Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interests</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/interests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 12:03:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/interests/</guid>
      <description>My first experience in research, working in a molecular immunology lab isolating B cells and evaluating their cytokine expression, fostered in me a deep interest in molecular biology. During my Erasmus I became interested in the ecological aspect of biology and took courses in limnology and marine biology. Not neglecting the molecular opportunities there, I also attended courses in human physiology and evolutionary genetics.
During my Master’s studies, I became interested in linking the broader ecological and behavioural impacts to underlying molecular mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 10:53:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://melaniewickert.de/sections/skills/</guid>
      <description> Cell culture, microscopy, immunostaining, FACS, B cell isolation, cell viability assays, PCR/qPCR, ELISA, SDS Page, Western Blot, Primer design, DNA/RNA isolation and microsatellite analysis, genetic and behavioural data collection in the field
 Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Photoshop; Basics in GraphPad Prism, Matlab, Processing, Python, OpenCV, Java, and R
 Project planning and management, data collection, experimental design
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>